<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Benoit Gaüzère website</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Benoit Gaüzère website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bgauzere.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Participation to S+SSPR 2024 in Venice</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/sspr_2024/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/sspr_2024/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="ssspr-2024">S+SSPR 2024&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>For this edition of S+SSPR 2024, I had the pleasure to present our work entitled
&lt;a href="./Evaluation_of_a_Continuous_Approximation_of_GED.pdf">A Differentiable Approximation of the Graph Edit Distance&lt;/a>. This paper, not
in its camera ready version yet, consists in an adaptation of the well known
Sinkhorn algorithm to replace the Hungarian algorithm to solve the LSAPE problem
related to the approximation of the graph edit distance. The main advantage of
this approach is to be differentiable, which opens a path to compute the graph
edit distance, and edit costs, in an end to end manner.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PhD Opportunity GNN and Brain data</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/famous_these_2024/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/famous_these_2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="./brain_famous.png" alt="Brain Graphs">&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="alert-2006--the-phd-student-has-been-chosen-thank-you-for-your-interest">ALERT 20/06 : The Phd student has been chosen, thank you for your interest&lt;/h1>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="unlocking-the-mysteries-of-the-brain-with-graph-based-machine-learning">Unlocking the Mysteries of the Brain with Graph-Based Machine Learning&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the fascinating world of neuroscience, understanding the brain&amp;rsquo;s
intricate structure is key to unlocking the secrets of psychiatric and
neurological disorders. Imagine if we could map the brain&amp;rsquo;s folds and curves
to reveal patterns that indicate health or disease. This is precisely what our
cutting-edge PhD project aims to achieve, leveraging the power of graph-based machine learning (GML) and Graph Neural Networks (GNN).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SWERC 2024 - Competitive Programming</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/swerc_2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/swerc_2024/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-competition">The Competition&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Late january 2024, I accompanied students of INSA Rouen to a competition of
competitive programming : the SWERC 2024 in Paris (&lt;a href="https://swerc.eu/2023/)">https://swerc.eu/2023/)&lt;/a>. This
contest is an international contest between teams of universities from 6 south western
Europe countries, part of the more global ICPC. The contest consists in solving 13 problems of different
difficulties using raw Python, C++ or other languages in 5 hours. Each problem
is a statement with some rules, and must be solved under some constraints which
forbids a naive and straightforward implementation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Advent of Code 2023</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/aoc2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/aoc2023/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="advent-of-code-2023">Advent of code 2023&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>For the second year, I spent too much time in December to solve the problems of
the &lt;strong>advent of code&lt;/strong> : &lt;a href="https://adventofcode.com/">https://adventofcode.com/&lt;/a>. Finally, I was quite happy to
get the 50 stars. I really like this challenge because it&amp;rsquo;s very well designed
from an algorithmic point of view. Each problem is divided into two
levels. Generally the first one can be solved by using a brute force and naive
strategy, while the second part generally requires to find some tricks to
accelerate the computation and find the right solution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Master Internship on GNN and Fair Machine Learning</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/intern_famous/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/intern_famous/</guid><description>&lt;p>Starting in next february/march, we are looking at a master student to work at
the interface of Graph Neural Networks and fair machine learning. This
internship will be part of ANR FAMOUS project, with a close collaboration with
INT of Marseille.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The internship will located in Rouen, with App Team of LITIS Lab.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More details on the internship in this &lt;a href="internship_position.pdf">document&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Feel free to reach me if you are interested !&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Machine Learning on Graph Working Group</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/gt_graphes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/gt_graphes/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="brain_graph.jpg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.litislab.fr/equipe/app">App Team&lt;/a> at the &lt;a href="https://www.litislab.fr/">LITIS Lab&lt;/a> boasts significant expertise in graph-based machine learning, a field we have been engaged in for many years. Our team&amp;rsquo;s focus has intensified recently, especially due to the burgeoning interest in machine learning applications for graph data. Collaborative efforts with the &lt;a href="https://www.greyc.fr/">GREYC&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://lifat.univ-tours.fr">LIFAT&lt;/a> labs have further helped us consolidate our focus in this domain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our involvement in the &lt;a href="https://www.normastic.fr/analyse-de-graphes-appliquee-a-la-chemoinformatique/">AGAC project&lt;/a> marked a pivotal point, leading to notable discoveries in the realm of Graph Neural Networks, as documented in our publications [&lt;a href="https://normandie-univ.hal.science/hal-03135633/">1&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://proceedings.mlr.press/v139/balcilar21a.html">2&lt;/a>]. Building on these achievements, we embarked on the ambitious &lt;a href="https://www.normastic.fr/projet-anr-codegnn/">ANR CodeGNN project&lt;/a>. This project aims to delve into three key areas: convolution techniques, pooling methods in Graph Neural Networks (GNNs), and the application of GNNs to spatio-temporal graph data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A new school year just begun</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/insa_2023_2024/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/insa_2023_2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>A new school year has just begun at &lt;a href="https://www.insa-rouen.fr/">INSA Rouen
Normandie&lt;/a>, providing an opportunity to introduce the various courses in which I am involved:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://moodle.insa-rouen.fr/course/view.php?id=159">Ananum.&lt;/a> In this course, we teach numerical methods for solving linear problems using LU, PALU, Cholesky, and other matrix decomposition techniques. We also delve into SVD problems and iterative methods.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://moodle.insa-rouen.fr/course/view.php?id=92">Introduction to Machine
Learning.&lt;/a> Before delving into deep learning and its extensive ecosystem, we revisit the fundamentals and explore alternative methods. It&amp;rsquo;s essential to keep an eye on various aspects! In this lesson, we cover topics such as clustering, evaluation protocols, optimization, SVM, Bayesian methods, and more.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://moodle.insa-rouen.fr/course/view.php?id=1206">Operationnal
Research.&lt;/a> Apart from machine learning, many problem-solving
approaches rely on pure algorithms. In this course, we delve into resolution
methods based on graphs, including the renowned Fulkerson algorithm, graph
theory, and graph isomorphism problems. We also discuss how to model problems
effectively.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>We look forward to reconvening in January for the second-semester courses !&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Two new ANR projects and one paper at ACPR 2023</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/anr_2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/anr_2023/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="two-new-anr-projects-for-2023">Two new ANR projects for 2023&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>For this year, two projects have been funded. First, &lt;strong>ANR FAMOUS&lt;/strong> will focus on designing fair ML models, including models operating on graphs. This page will be updated with the link to the projects for further details. Note that we will seek for PhD students to work on this topic. Feel free to drop an email if interested. Second, &lt;strong>ANR OOD&lt;/strong> is an ANR project dedicating to the App team of LITIS. In this project, we will focus on anomaly detection. More to come soon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Participation to GbR 2023 in Salerno</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/gbr_2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/gbr_2023/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="gbr-2023-">GbR 2023 !&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Together with Paul Honeine, Luc Brun and the two PhD students Stevan Stanovic et
Clément Gledel, we have two papers accepted in IAPR TC 15 conference :
Graph-based Representations for Pattern Recognition which will be held in
Salerno next september.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The two papers are :&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Graph Normalizing Flows to Pre-image Free Machine Learning for Regression&lt;/strong>,
with &lt;strong>Clément Gledel&lt;/strong> and Paul Honeine on the definition of machine learning
models operating on graphs without the problem of preimage, hence bringing
explicability to our models.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Recrutement thèse GRANIT - Caractérisation des dynamiques spatiales dans le cadre de sources géolocalisées et non géolocalisée</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/these_granit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/these_granit/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="caractérisation-des-dynamiques-spatiales-dans-le-cadre-de-sources-géolocalisées-et-non-géolocalisée">Caractérisation des dynamiques spatiales dans le cadre de sources géolocalisées et non géolocalisée&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Démarrage&lt;/strong> : septembre 2023&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Contacts&lt;/strong> : &lt;a href="mailto:geraldine.del_mondo@insa-rouen.fr">geraldine.del_mondo@insa-rouen.fr&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="mailto:benoit.gauzere@insa-rouen.fr">benoit.gauzere@insa-rouen.fr&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Lieu&lt;/strong> : LITIS, INSA Rouen&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Profil attendu&lt;/strong> : Master 2 en informatique/IA, des compétences minimales en
théorie des graphes sont requises&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Salaire mensuel brut&lt;/strong> : 2044,12 euros&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mots clés&lt;/strong> : algorithme de graphe, extraction de patterns spatio-temporel,
isomorphismes de graphes, application aux données historiques, modélisation par graphes, analyse spatio-temporelle&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="these_granit.pdf">&lt;strong>Sujet de thèse&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Implémentation de différents tests d'isomorphisme de graphes</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/graph_isomorphism/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/graph_isomorphism/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Dans ce document, nous allons implémenter différents algorithmes d&amp;rsquo;isomorphismes de sous graphes, optimaux ou non.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dans un premier temps, nous allons nous concentrer sur 3 algorithmes différents, à savoir :&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Weisfeler-Lehman : revenu à la mode avec le noyau sur graphe puis les graph neural network&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Morgan Numbering (TODO): utilisé en chimie, assez similaire à Weisfeler-Lehman dans le principe&lt;/li>
&lt;li>VF2 (TODO): un algorithme d&amp;rsquo;isomorphisme de graphes reconnu, dévellopé au MIVIA lab de Salerno&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="création-des-graphes">Création des graphes&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Avant d&amp;rsquo;implémenter les algos, nous allons créer 3 graphes simples à visualiser. Deux d&amp;rsquo;entre eux ($G_1$ et $G_3$) sont isormorphes. C&amp;rsquo;est à dire qu&amp;rsquo;ils représentent le même graphe, mais que l&amp;rsquo;ordre des noeuds de chacun des graphes est différent. Il y a une permutation des nœuds.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Teaching activities</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/teaching/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 14:06:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/teaching/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="teaching-activities">Teaching activities&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Most of my teaching activities are done at &lt;a href="https://www.insa-rouen.fr/">INSA Rouen
Normandie&lt;/a>, within the computer engineering
(&lt;a href="https://www.insa-rouen.fr/formation/specialites-ingenieurses/informatique-et-technologie-de-linformation">ITI&lt;/a>)
department.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here a list with ressources to my principal courses.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://moodle.insa-rouen.fr/course/view.php?id=159">Analyse Numérique&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Matrix factorization (LU,QR,Cholesky), linear systems, eigensystems, iterative methods and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://moodle.insa-rouen.fr/course/view.php?id=60">Algorithmique&lt;/a> (resp. Nicolas Delestre)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>C programming, collections, dynamic data structure, advanced algortihms.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://moodle.insa-rouen.fr/course/view.php?id=169">Statistics&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Introduction to statistics and data science including descriptive statistics, linear
regression and statistical signifiance tests.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://moodle.unistra.fr/course/view.php?id=999">Introduction to Machine Learning&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>A course given at &lt;a href="https://www.ufaz.az/">UFAZ&lt;/a>, a Franco-Azerbaijani university. It
focuses on basics of machine learning including unsupervised (KMeans, PCA) and supervised
(Ridge Regression, SVM) methods. It also includes evaluation protocol and theory.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/research/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="research-activities">Research Activities&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>My current research lies at the interface of graph based representation of data and
the definition of machine learning methods operating on graphs. In my recent works, I
focused on :&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>learning edit costs for graph edit distance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>improve pooling layer for GNN : pooling&lt;/li>
&lt;li>define methods to alleviate the problem of preimage of graphs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>apply graph based machine learning methods to chemoinformatics&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>An up to date list of publications can be found at &lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=YqmqE9gAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=fr">Google
Scholar&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>