<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Benoit Gaüzère website</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Benoit Gaüzère website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://bgauzere.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Teaching activities</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/teaching/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 14:06:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/teaching/</guid><description>Teaching activities Most of my teaching activities are done at INSA Rouen Normandie, within the computer engineering (ITI) department.
Here a list with ressources to my principal courses.
Analyse Numérique Matrix factorization (LU,QR,Cholesky), linear systems, eigensystems, iterative methods and more.
Algorithmique (resp. Nicolas Delestre) C programming, collections, dynamic data structure, advanced algortihms.
Statistics Introduction to statistics and data science including descriptive statistics, linear regression and statistical signifiance tests.
Introduction to Machine Learning A course given at UFAZ, a Franco-Azerbaijani university.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/research/</guid><description>Research Activities My current research lies at the interface of graph based representation of data and the definition of machine learning methods operating on graphs. In my recent works, I focused on :
learning edit costs for graph edit distanceI&amp;rsquo;m currently working at improve pooling layer for GNN : poolinga define methods to alleviate the problem of preimage of graphs apply graph based machine learning methods to chemoinformatics An up to date list of publications can be found at Google Scholar.</description></item></channel></rss>