<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Benoit Gaüzère website</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Benoit Gaüzère website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bgauzere.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Implémentation de différents tests d'isomorphisme de graphes</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/graph_isomorphism/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/graph_isomorphism/</guid><description>Introduction Dans ce document, nous allons implémenter différents algorithmes d&amp;rsquo;isomorphismes de sous graphes, optimaux ou non.
Dans un premier temps, nous allons nous concentrer sur 3 algorithmes différents, à savoir :
Weisfeler-Lehman : revenu à la mode avec le noyau sur graphe puis les graph neural network Morgan Numbering (TODO): utilisé en chimie, assez similaire à Weisfeler-Lehman dans le principe VF2 (TODO): un algorithme d&amp;rsquo;isomorphisme de graphes reconnu, dévellopé au MIVIA lab de Salerno Création des graphes Avant d&amp;rsquo;implémenter les algos, nous allons créer 3 graphes simples à visualiser.</description></item><item><title>Teaching activities</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/teaching/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 14:06:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/teaching/</guid><description>Teaching activities Most of my teaching activities are done at INSA Rouen Normandie, within the computer engineering (ITI) department.
Here a list with ressources to my principal courses.
Analyse Numérique Matrix factorization (LU,QR,Cholesky), linear systems, eigensystems, iterative methods and more.
Algorithmique (resp. Nicolas Delestre) C programming, collections, dynamic data structure, advanced algortihms.
Statistics Introduction to statistics and data science including descriptive statistics, linear regression and statistical signifiance tests.
Introduction to Machine Learning A course given at UFAZ, a Franco-Azerbaijani university.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/research/</guid><description>Research Activities My current research lies at the interface of graph based representation of data and the definition of machine learning methods operating on graphs. In my recent works, I focused on :
learning edit costs for graph edit distanceI&amp;rsquo;m currently working at improve pooling layer for GNN : poolinga define methods to alleviate the problem of preimage of graphs apply graph based machine learning methods to chemoinformatics An up to date list of publications can be found at Google Scholar.</description></item></channel></rss>