<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News on Benoit Gaüzère website</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/</link><description>Recent content in News on Benoit Gaüzère website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bgauzere.github.io/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Advent of Code 2023</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/aoc2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/aoc2023/</guid><description>Advent of code 2023 For the second year, I spent too much time in December to solve the problems of the advent of code : https://adventofcode.com/. Finally, I was quite happy to get the 50 stars. I really like this challenge because it&amp;rsquo;s very well designed from an algorithmic point of view. Each problem is divided into two levels. Generally the first one can be solved by using a brute force and naive strategy, while the second part generally requires to find some tricks to accelerate the computation and find the right solution.</description></item><item><title>Master Internship on GNN and Fair Machine Learning</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/intern_famous/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/intern_famous/</guid><description>Starting in next february/march, we are looking at a master student to work at the interface of Graph Neural Networks and fair machine learning. This internship will be part of ANR FAMOUS project, with a close collaboration with INT of Marseille.
The internship will located in Rouen, with App Team of LITIS Lab.
More details on the internship in this document
Feel free to reach me if you are interested !</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning on Graph Working Group</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/gt_graphes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/gt_graphes/</guid><description>The App Team at the LITIS Lab boasts significant expertise in graph-based machine learning, a field we have been engaged in for many years. Our team&amp;rsquo;s focus has intensified recently, especially due to the burgeoning interest in machine learning applications for graph data. Collaborative efforts with the GREYC and LIFAT labs have further helped us consolidate our focus in this domain.
Our involvement in the AGAC project marked a pivotal point, leading to notable discoveries in the realm of Graph Neural Networks, as documented in our publications [1, 2].</description></item><item><title>A new school year just begun</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/insa_2023_2024/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/insa_2023_2024/</guid><description>A new school year has just begun at INSA Rouen Normandie, providing an opportunity to introduce the various courses in which I am involved:
Ananum. In this course, we teach numerical methods for solving linear problems using LU, PALU, Cholesky, and other matrix decomposition techniques. We also delve into SVD problems and iterative methods. Introduction to Machine Learning. Before delving into deep learning and its extensive ecosystem, we revisit the fundamentals and explore alternative methods.</description></item><item><title>Two new ANR projects and one paper at ACPR 2023</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/anr_2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/anr_2023/</guid><description>Two new ANR projects for 2023 For this year, two projects have been funded. First, ANR FAMOUS will focus on designing fair ML models, including models operating on graphs. This page will be updated with the link to the projects for further details. Note that we will seek for PhD students to work on this topic. Feel free to drop an email if interested. Second, ANR OOD is an ANR project dedicating to the App team of LITIS.</description></item><item><title>Participation to GbR 2023 in Salerno</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/gbr_2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/gbr_2023/</guid><description>GbR 2023 ! Together with Paul Honeine, Luc Brun and the two PhD students Stevan Stanovic et Clément Gledel, we have two papers accepted in IAPR TC 15 conference : Graph-based Representations for Pattern Recognition which will be held in Salerno next september.
The two papers are :
Graph Normalizing Flows to Pre-image Free Machine Learning for Regression, with Clément Gledel and Paul Honeine on the definition of machine learning models operating on graphs without the problem of preimage, hence bringing explicability to our models.</description></item><item><title>Recrutement thèse GRANIT - Caractérisation des dynamiques spatiales dans le cadre de sources géolocalisées et non géolocalisée</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/these_granit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/these_granit/</guid><description>Caractérisation des dynamiques spatiales dans le cadre de sources géolocalisées et non géolocalisée Démarrage : septembre 2023 Contacts : geraldine.del_mondo@insa-rouen.fr, benoit.gauzere@insa-rouen.fr Lieu : LITIS, INSA Rouen Profil attendu : Master 2 en informatique/IA, des compétences minimales en théorie des graphes sont requises Salaire mensuel brut : 2044,12 euros Mots clés : algorithme de graphe, extraction de patterns spatio-temporel, isomorphismes de graphes, application aux données historiques, modélisation par graphes, analyse spatio-temporelle Sujet de thèse</description></item><item><title>Implémentation de différents tests d'isomorphisme de graphes</title><link>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/graph_isomorphism/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bgauzere.github.io/news/graph_isomorphism/</guid><description>Introduction Dans ce document, nous allons implémenter différents algorithmes d&amp;rsquo;isomorphismes de sous graphes, optimaux ou non.
Dans un premier temps, nous allons nous concentrer sur 3 algorithmes différents, à savoir :
Weisfeler-Lehman : revenu à la mode avec le noyau sur graphe puis les graph neural network Morgan Numbering (TODO): utilisé en chimie, assez similaire à Weisfeler-Lehman dans le principe VF2 (TODO): un algorithme d&amp;rsquo;isomorphisme de graphes reconnu, dévellopé au MIVIA lab de Salerno Création des graphes Avant d&amp;rsquo;implémenter les algos, nous allons créer 3 graphes simples à visualiser.</description></item></channel></rss>